

# Vincent Stragier

## **Electrical Engineer**



1997



7522 Blandain, Belgique



+32 65 37 42 61



in/vincentstragier



vincent.stragier@outlook.com

Driving licence and car (Euro 6)

# About me ——

Willing to go above and beyond the technical barriers. Interested in electronics related product design and biomedical research. Open source and open hardware adept. Amateur photograph of nature, astronomical object and people. Soldering iron master.

# Skills –

Python (on cluster, computer and RPi)

**₽T**FX

FreeRTOS API (on Espressif chips)

C++ (on Arduino, Espressif and STM)

Public speaking

Electronics (KiCad, LTSpice)

Photography (DSLR)

Curiosity \*6 Perseverance \*5 Perfectionism \*5

 $(\sp{*})[\mbox{The skill scale}$  is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

#### **Experience**

2021-Present ISIA Lab

PhD Student

Research related to the developpment of an intelligent assistant

for visually impaired people.

2020-2021

**Engineering Student Intern** 

Consolidate an epileptic seizure detection pipeline using machine learning on the Temple University Hospital EEG Seizure Corpus (supervised by Paul Vanabelle and Thierry Dutoit).

Development of a tool for anonymization and conversion of electroencephalographic (EEG) files to facilitate the construction and

exchange of a dataset.

2018-Present Codobot®

Hardware and Firmware developer

Design of a printed circuit board, associated firmware, flashing and testing tools for the robot integrated to the Codobot® board

2017-Present electroLAB

President (19-Present), VP (18-19), Treasurer (17-18)

Organise the main events and realise electronics related projects, i.e., micro-controller based wheel encoder decoder counter (contribution to the Faculty's Eurobot team), Arduino related workshops (Créactifs!), connected bird houses allowing to observe birds through a network of video cameras (for Tanguy Du-

mortier, RTBF)

2022-Present Erasmus Student Network (Mons)

Website deployement and technical maintenance.

2020-2021 Erasmus Student Network (Mons)

City Trips

ΙT

Support the organisation of trips within the country, photograph

trips, and generally inform Erasmus students

2015-2016 Jeunesses Scientifiques Belges (Mons)

**Activity Leader** 

Design and lead of workshops for young people aged 13 to 17

#### Education

2021-Present ISIA Lab

PhD Student

University of Mons, Belgium

2019-2021 Signals, Systems and BioEngineering

> Master's degree in Electrical Engineering University of Mons, Belgium

2015-2019 Bachelor's degree in Engineering - Electricity

> Bachelor's degree in Engineering University of Mons, Belgium

Sciences Appliquées 2011-2015

High School Diploma

Centre Éducatif de la Sainte-Union, Tournai

# Tools

· Visual Studio Code

· Microsoft Word and Excel

GitHub (and GitHub actions)

SolidWorks

 Windows and Linux (down to CLI usage)

SLURM

### Accomplishments

2021 Technord Best master thesis

Prize issued by Technord for the best master thesis in the finality

Signals, Systems and BioEngineering.

2019 Créactifs! Conception of the Codobot® robot

Prize issued by UMONS for the Tangerine project video. Design  $\,$ 

of a robot prototype within a multidisciplinary team

2017 Startech Domogrid entrepreneurial project

Prize issued by WSL for the best entrepreneurial team project for the StarTech contest within the UMONS Faculty of Engineering. Post project presentation at Texas A&M University to Rodney

Hill's students

2017 Créactifs! Domogrid MVP

UMONS prize won for the Domogrid project video, alongside

Charles Dehombreux and Yannick Molle

#### Languages

French C2, Native language Italian Beginner

English B1, IELTS (2018)